(Watch on KonFlix.vip)
Ayaka.
Here's your lunch.
I put in your favorite Hamburg steak
to cheer you up!
Thanks.
-Be careful.
-Okay.
Bye.
You've got this!
MUSASHINO KITA MIDDLE SCHOOL
YUKANAI
NOW ACCEPTING NEW STUDENTS!
Ready, smash!
Oh, no.
I'm losing.
Yuuki. What are you making?
An alien. An evil one.
Oh, that's scary. Should we take him down?
How should we do it?
Wanna make something?
No, it's okay.
Okay.
Forget it!
-I'm sick of this!
-Whoa!
That's right! Take 'em down!
Yuuki!
The demon's here.
Come at me!
Shut up!
Oh… um…
I'm sorry.
I'm here for the interview.
-Great timing.
-Um…
Put this on.
‎What?
Yuuki! The blue demon is here too.
What?
Go away!
-Go get 'em!
-Wait a minute!
Throw harder!
What?
-Hold on! It hurts.
-Come get me!
Ouch!
350,000 CHILDREN EXPERIENCE SCHOOL REFUSAL
WHAT'S AN ALTERNATIVE SCHOOL?
A PLACE TO RECLAIM AND NURTURE YOURSELF
"THIRD SAFE HAVEN"
ASIDE FROM SCHOOL OR HOME
Those guys really don't hold back.
They're always like that.
Anyway, you're here
for the interview, right?
Yes.
-Please sit.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Okay.
I'm here on a referral
from Professor Mikumo.
I'm scheduled to have an interview
with the manager.
Um… Where's the manager?
That's me.
Oh, I apologize.
I'm Tatsuki Ukita, the manager.
I'm Shizuku Aomine.
Ao…
Aom…
-Aomine…
-Shizuku Aomine.
Please just call me Shizuku.
-Ms. Shizuku.
-Yes.
You were…
You were a teacher
at Musashino Daihachi Middle School?
Yes.
I worked as a teacher
for about five years,
but I left due to personal reasons.
Why this alternative school?
I really want to continue working
with children.
You play video games?
-What?
-Video games.
I've never played them before.
Then what about shogi,
card games, or board games?
Sorry, no.
I see.
Any other special skills?
I can tutor.
For Japanese and English,
I can teach from basics to advanced.
That's not what I meant.
Do you own a hoodie?
-Hoodie?
-Yeah.
Yes, I believe so.
Okay.
But you can't play games, huh.
Tatsuki.
They want to go outside.
I want to play color tag.
Good idea.
Let's see…
What should I do?
I'll contact you
with the results at a later date.
Thank you.
Um…
I…
didn't go to school for six years
starting in middle school.
So I think I understand
the feelings of kids
experiencing school refusal.
That's my special skill!
You're hired.
I'm Soya Kaido, a volunteer staff member.
Everyone calls me Soya.
Mr. Soya.
I'm Shizuku Aomine.
-Nice to meet you.
Everyone here calls each other
by nicknames.
What would you like yours to be?
A nickname?
Then…
Please call me Shi-chan.
Very nice!
Attention everyone!
This is Shi-chan, who will be joining
as the newest staff member!
-Hello.
-Shi-chan.
-Shi-chan!
-Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Whoa, watch out. Don't cut me.
Basically, everyone here just hangs out
and does whatever they feel like doing.
They can do homework,
play games,
or even just take a nap
like that kid over there.
There are no specific rules here?
Well, they have to put their belongings
in a locker when they get here.
And they have to throw away trash
in the wastebasket.
Throw trash in the wastebasket.
I see.
I know there are various types
of alternative schools,
but what type is this…
This is the safe haven type.
Safe haven type.
This is the kitchen and dining room area.
They're making lunch?
Yeah. Hey guys, what's on the menu today?
Curry with fried chicken and salad.
How many layers of the onion do I peel?
I'll do it.
All right.
Hello. I'm Ajiki.
Hello.
I'm Shizuku Aomine.
Call me Shi-chan.
I'm Ajicchan. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
Everyone cooks together?
Once a week.
And participation is optional.
We all decide on the menu together.
We made gratin last week.
-Oh.
-I see.
Please make the salad.
Just tear up the lettuce.
-Oh, but…
-Thanks.
Just tear it?
-Let's see…
-Oh!
Shi-chan, can you show the guests
to the atelier?
-Me?
-Yeah, sorry.
I'm Saotome.
Say hello.
She's Ayaka.
She had been skipping school
on and off during the first year
of middle school,
but ever since she started
the second year,
she's been unable to go to school at all.
I see.
Lately, her days and nights
have gotten completely flipped around,
and her lifestyle is irregular,
so I'm hoping to get her back
to a normal routine.
All this artwork was drawn
by the kids here.
Isn't this interesting?
Since she's been refusing
to go to school for so long,
I'm worried that she'll fall behind
on her studies.
That's understandable.
How are the kids here studying…?
They hardly study at all.
They usually play games,
go outside to play, or draw.
I'm sorry.
I'm usually playing games
until late at night,
so I'm sleep-deprived every day.
-I see.
-Yup.
If you want to get her to study,
you'll be better off throwing away
the textbooks altogether.
‎What?
I actually used to work
as a middle school teacher.
So I can help out with the schoolwork.
I see.
Good for you.
Did Ayaka say
that she wanted to come here?
I checked the reviews online,
and when I told her about this place,
she said she wanted to check it out.
I see.
How long do people stay here
for their school refusal to be cured?
It's not something that can be cured.
Not going to school is also a way of life.
But in that case, what about her future…
What matters more is the present,
not the future.
Do you have any other concerns?
No, thank you.
Okay.
While you're here,
only do things that you think are fun.
Want to draw something?
Let's see.
This might be good.
-Thank you for the food.
-Let's eat.
Yummy!
It's delicious!
Make sure you chew your food.
Curry is not a drink, got it?
Stop that.
I understand you must be worried.
Yes.
I'm not really sure what's troubling her.
Even when I ask, she won't tell me.
Did anything change around the time
she started the second year?
For example, were there any school events?
You can draw whatever you want.
All right.
Okay.
How about we play word chain art?
I'll start.
Let's see.
Your turn.
All right.
Let's see what I can do.
Maybe I'll add color to it.
When you use your finger
to blend the color like this…
It looks good, right?
If we're going to use soft pastels…
This drawing paper would be best.
Here.
Is that a sparrow?
That looks good. Draw some more.
That one is all alone.
I guess so.
I see.
How does that sparrow feel?
This area is empty. Can I draw here?
You drew a sparrow,
so I'll draw the next one.
Let's see, I'll draw…
I don't know.
Let's continue this next time.
NOT GOING TO SCHOOL
IS ALSO ONE WAY OF LIFE
-Bye.
-Be careful.
Sorry for causing you so much trouble.
Not at all.
Throwing that playdough
helped you blow off steam, right?
Bye.
It seems like he constantly
throws tantrums at school too.
You can do it.
-I did it!
-Yeah!
Stop it!
Whoa, let's get away from him!
I ask him why he'd do such a thing,
but to no avail.
-Bye.
Well,
if you ever feel like really letting loose
and throwing something again,
we've got Ms. Shizuku here.
Hold on, I'm not a shooting target.
-I'm really sorry.
-It's all right.
We'll be going now.
Bye.
Ayaka. See you again.
I'm back.
Welcome home. How was it?
I drew.
That's good.
I'm glad you had fun.
About school tomorrow…
Never mind.
Good work, everyone.
-Hello, Professor.
-Hello.
I started working here today.
This is Shi-chan.
-I'm Shi-chan.
-Shi-chan?
-Nice to meet you.
-Likewise.
This is for everyone.
You were on a trip?
It was an academic conference
for art therapy.
Oh, right.
What's art therapy?
I'm not entirely sure myself,
but I guess it's something like
expressing your feelings
and finding healing through art.
Shi-chan, how was your first day?
Well, it was one surprise after another.
I realized everyone
is free to do whatever they want.
Whether that's drawing or playing games.
That's right.
Yeah, our policy is to leave everything
up to the kids.
They're free to play video games,
and free to do sports.
-Right?
-Yeah.
But Ayaka's mother, who visited today,
was worried about her daughter's studies.
Mr. Tatsuki told her
that if she wants her to study,
she should throw away her textbooks.
It's true that for some kids,
seeing textbooks lined up on the shelf
can become a source of pressure.
So, one approach is to remove the books
out of sight once
and wait until they regain
the desire to study again.
I see.
That's why they need to be tossed.
They shouldn't be tossed away.
Ayaka was drawing today.
Oh, she drew, huh?
I want to take a look at it.
-This way.
-Let me see it.
First we played word chain art,
then she drew this.
Did she mention anything about school?
No, nothing.
I see.
Um…
I heard from Ayaka's mother today…
Did anything change around the time
she started the second year?
There was a field trip.
Field trip, huh.
Something might've happened
between her and her friends.
Can I look into this a little?
No need to do that.
It's better to resolve this quickly.
I know a few teachers
at Kita Middle School.
I think she'll tell us the details
when she's ready to.
Now, now.
Just ask around casually.
Okay.
By the way, how's that kid
who throws tantrums?
Yuuki?
How's he doing?
I allowed him
to really let loose today, but…
-Get away!
-Ouch!
Strike 'em down!
I honestly don't know if that was
the right thing to do.
Then the next step
is to figure out how to help him
control those emotions.
Control?
Well, I'm off now.
Bye.
Don't come in here!
Go away!
Sora! Open up!
MUSASHINO KITA MIDDLE SCHOOL
Ms. Aomine,
long time no see.
Sorry to bother you like this.
Not at all.
We want to address the issue
of school refusal as soon as possible,
-so this is actually a big help.
-Thank you.
He was in the same group as her
during the field trip,
and he seems to know a little
about the situation.
Sorry to bother you during lunch.
Not at all.
Do you have any idea why Ayaka
stopped coming to school?
It's probably
my fault.
Hey, it's almost time to meet up
with everyone.
You're not done yet?
We'll be going now.
Let's go.
I didn't say anything more
and we left her there.
Thanks for telling me.
That's so cool.
-Damn it!
-Yuuki!
Yuuki.
This car is just like you.
-What?
-Look.
It has the ability to go super-fast!
When it's angry,
it has strong attack power.
That's like me?
Try driving it yourself.
Try driving it slowly.
Vroom, vroom.
-Vroom, vroom.
-Good.
Make it go even slower.
I want it to go faster.
Then try gradually increasing the speed.
-Vroom, vroom!
-That's good!
Little by little. Good job.
Yuuki. Stop.
Stop!
Good job, Yuuki. Excellent driver.
Hey.
If you ever reach a point
when you feel overwhelmed,
think about this car.
Mr. Tatsuki.
So according to that group leader,
the source of the issue
might be the fact that Ayaka
ended up getting left behind
because she was so absorbed
with her drawing.
And then?
It seems he's going to apologize
to Ayaka in person today.
We're very sorry.
Not at all.
Thank you for coming all the way here.
See you at school.
Thank you for your time today.
Thank you.
I see.
So that's what happened?
But it's nice that he came to apologize.
Can you go to school?
Yeah.
Okay.
I'm glad! I'm really glad.
Good morning.
That's nice.
-It's crazy, right?
-Yeah.
So then what happened?
Playing any games lately?
First period we have music.
-Oh, no.
-Oh, crap.
I totally forgot.
Let's hurry.
Oh no.
This is bad.
Ayaka
hasn't come back after that one time.
It seems like she went to school today.
I hope things are going well.
Yeah.
I've experienced school refusal myself,
but the longer it drags on,
the harder it gets to go back.
Is that right?
That's why I can kind of understand
Ayaka's feelings.
Hello, it's Yukanai.
Is Ayaka there?
No, she's not here.
I just got a call from her school.
It seems she left school
without telling anyone.
I'll search for her too.
Shall we continue drawing
where we left off?
‎What?
Here.
With pastels,
you can erase them if you want,
or you can layer them.
You're free to do whatever.
I wonder why she left school early.
Yeah, I wonder.
Do you like to draw?
When I was in college,
I spent all my time drawing.
Can you draw too, Teacher?
Call me Tatsuki.
Tatsuki, draw with me.
What's that?
It's a birdcage.
Those birds are in the birdcage?
Then
is that other bird
planning to fly off somewhere?
I don't know.
I see.
Ayaka's mother contacted us.
She said Ayaka just got back home.
Did you understand anything
from her drawings?
Nope.
I don't know what Ayaka is going through.
Is it still difficult
even with art therapy?
It doesn't always give us direct answers.
Could it be
that this birdcage and the sparrows
represent her school and friends?
From Ayaka's perspective
maybe there's this insurmountable wall
keeping her from going to school.
She doesn't need to go.
You don't have to force yourself
to go to school.
Those who want to should go.
That's not how it works.
Ms. Shizuku, you sound just like
a schoolteacher.
Couldn't you be a little more flexible
in your thinking?
No.
Just imagine how worried parents get
when their child won't go to school.
I'm sure deep down Ayaka knows this too.
She wants to go but she can't.
But if she continues to stay home,
she knows she'll never
be able to go at all.
That's why
she makes the effort to go.
No one needs to force themselves to go.
What?
I'm going to step out.
Take care of things here.
He's so annoying!
Shi-chan, eat slowly.
What's wrong with that guy?
He's got a super naive mindset,
but is he all right?
I totally understand. It's worrisome, huh?
I understand that this place
is necessary
for children who have been hurt.
But it's only natural for parents
to be worried about their children's
studies and their future.
You're right.
And yet he says kids should be free
and not be forced to go to school.
Isn't that just completely irresponsible?
I understand,
but that's too much hot sauce.
Sorry.
Personally, I think it's great to have
different perspectives.
Given your background as a teacher,
you're able to empathize
with parents' feelings.
That's necessary here too.
Thank you.
Well, it seems like he has his own way
of dealing with things.
Or so I think.
He's so annoying!
I thought the problem was solved.
The other kid apologized, right?
But she left school early, so I think
there's something else going on.
Like what?
What did Ayaka say?
I've asked her, but she won't tell me.
But even so,
we can't just leave this problem alone.
And what if she falls behind
in her studies?
She's the one who'll struggle
in the future.
It's best to solve this
as soon as possible.
Yeah.
I'll be off.
Bye.
-Wait up.
-Okay.
-You can't run into the street.
-I can do a new trick.
-Just watch.
-Go play over there.
Okay.
Oh.
Ayaka.
Ta-da!
A 242-color set of soft pastels!
There were so many colors
I had run out of.
So I decided to splurge.
I see.
Look at this.
The gradation from green to blue
is so cool, isn't it?
Yeah, it's cool.
Here.
Go ahead.
Feel free to use it.
It's raining?
That sparrow will get wet.
What's it going to do?
Tatsuki.
I don't
want to go to school.
I see.
You were able to express your feelings.
If
you have something you want to say,
don't keep it bottled up inside.
You can talk about anything you like here.
Okay,
you don't want to go to school, huh.
I've always been scared
of being in the classroom.
But
I couldn't tell anyone about it.
I see.
That's understandable.
And…
I can't tell Mom about this.
Okay.
I see.
I suppose the stifling pressure
of school life just gradually built up
over time.
But it's amazing that she was able
to voice that herself.
But she said she can't bring herself
to tell her mom yet.
It must be tough
when you can't reach out for help
-to the person closest to you.
-Yes.
I don't know how to help her.
To truly understand Ayaka's feelings,
you might need to take a deeper look
at whatever she focuses on
and pours her energy into.
I thought you hated schools.
I never said that.
You were totally against it.
I only got permission on the condition
that we stay in the hallway,
so please don't go into the classroom…
Hey, weren't you listening?
I want to look at the artwork
she drew at the zoo.
Oh, come on.
Hey.
MEMORIES FROM THE FIELD TRIP
There it is.
AYAKA SAOTOME
CLASS 2-2
Ms. Shizuku.
Yes?
Let's take this drawing.
No, you can't do that!
-What?
-You can't!
This is
what Ayaka drew when she was here.
It seems very lonely.
You're referring to this bird?
It looks lonely
being away from its friends.
I thought so too at first.
I thought this was the school,
and while everyone inside is having fun,
she couldn't break down the thick wall
to join everyone.
Yes.
But
I don't think these are her friends,
but her family instead.
What do you mean?
The birdcage isn't a wall
standing in her way,
but rather a barrier
that's protecting her.
Therefore, I don't think this represents
the school,
but her home instead.
Are you saying
that she wants to stay home?
Is there anything that comes to mind?
Well,
Ayaka has always said
that she wants to go to school.
But she told me
that she doesn't want to go to school.
What?
She said she can't bring herself
to tell you about it.
But why?
I didn't understand either, but…
Please take a look at this.
This is what Ayaka drew at the zoo.
When I look at this,
I get the sense
that this parent and child
share a deep bond
and place a great deal of trust
in one another.
That's how it seems
to me too.
I think Ayaka
couldn't bring herself
to express her true feelings
because her mother is so important to her.
Ayaka.
This
is a beautiful drawing.
The truth is,
I never wanted to go to school.
I'm sorry I never told you the truth.
It's all right.
I was always
a little too relieved whenever
you went to school, huh?
That's why you couldn't
tell me the truth, right?
I'm sorry.
Time to counterattack!
Stop!
Hooray!
When you feel overwhelmed,
think about this car.
Time to escape!
-No way.
-Hold on.
You're going to Yukanai today, right?
Here's your lunch.
I put in your favorite Hamburg steak
to cheer you up!
Thank you.
But right now, my favorite food
is kinpira gobo.
It is?
Since when?
Children grow up before you know it.
Oh, is that right?
Then I'll add that to your lunch
next time.
Thank you.
I'll be off.
Have fun.
Hello?
Tatsuki. Sora… Sora…
What happened to Sora?
He jumped.
What?
PREVIEW OF THE NEXT EPISODE
‎THIS DRAMA IS FICTION
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita